<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grimoire</title>
    <description>D&amp;D 5e spell list, sorted by class and level.</description>
    <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 19:06:37 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 19:06:37 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hypnotic Pattern</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: 120 feet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: S, M (a glowing stick of incense or a crystal vial filled with phosphorescent material)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 minute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You create a twisting pattern of colors that weaves through the air inside a 30-foot cube within range. The pattern appears for a moment and vanishes. Each creature in the area who sees the pattern must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature becomes charmed for the duration. While charmed by this spell, the creature is incapacitated and has a speed of 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spell ends for an affected creature if it takes any damage or if someone else uses an action to shake the creature out of its stupor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/hypnotic-pattern</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/hypnotic-pattern</guid>
        
        <category>bard</category>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>warlock</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hunger of Hadar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level conjuration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: 150 feet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a pickled octopus tentacle)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 minute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You open a gateway to the dark between the stars, a region infested with unknown horrors. A 20-foot-radius sphere of blackness and bitter cold appears, centered on a point with range and lasting for the duration. This void is filled with a cacophony of soft whispers and slurping noises that can be heard up to 30 feet away. No light, magical or otherwise, can illuminate the area, and creatures fully within the area are blinded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The void creates a warp in the fabric of space, and the area is difficult terrain. Any creature that starts its turn in the area takes 2d6 cold damage. Any creature that ends its turn in the area must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 acid damage as milky, otherworldly tentacles rub against it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/hunger-of-hadar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/hunger-of-hadar</guid>
        
        <category>warlock</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Haste</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level transmutation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: 30 feet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a shaving of licorice root)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 minute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a willing creature that you can see within range. Until the spell ends, the target’s speed is doubled, it gains a +2 bonus to AC, it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and it gains an additional action on each of its turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the spell ends, the target can’t move or take actions until after its next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/haste</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/haste</guid>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gaseous Form</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level transmutation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: Touch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a bit of gauze and a wisp of smoke)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You transform a willing creature you touch, along with everything it’s wearing and carrying, into a misty cloud for the duration. The spell ends if the creature drops to 0 hit points. An incorporeal creature isn’t affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in this form, the target’s only method of movement is a flying speed of 10 feet. The target can enter and occupy the space of another creature. The target has resistance to nonmagical damage, and it has advantage on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws. The target can pass through small holes, narrow openings, and even mere cracks, though it treats liquids as though they were solid surfaces. The target can’t fall and remains hovering in the air even when stunned or otherwise incapacitated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the form of a misty cloud, the target can’t talk or manipulate objects, and any objects it w as carrying or holding can’t be dropped, used, or otherwise interacted with. The target can’t attack or cast spells.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/gaseous-form</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/gaseous-form</guid>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level transmutation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: Touch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a wing feather from any bird)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 10 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature. The target gains a flying speed of 60 feet for the duration. When the spell ends, the target falls if it is still aloft, unless it can stop the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fly</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fly</guid>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>warlock</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fireball</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level evocation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: 150 feet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a tiny ball of bat quano and sulfur)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Instantaneous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range and then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fireball</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fireball</guid>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feign Death</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level necromancy (ritual)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: Touch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a pinch of graveyard dirt)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You touch a willing creature and put it into a cataleptic state that is indistinguishable from death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the spell’s duration, or until you use an action to touch the target and dismiss the spell, the target appears dead to all outward inspection and to spells used to determine the target’s status. The target is blinded and incapacitated, and its speed drops to 0. The target has resistance to all damage except psychic damage. If the target is diseased or poisoned when you cast the spell, or becomes diseased or poisoned while under the spell’s effect, the disease and poison have no effect until the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/feign-death</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/feign-death</guid>
        
        <category>bard</category>
        
        <category>cleric</category>
        
        <category>druid</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fear</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: Self (30-foot cone)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S, M (a white feather or the heart of a hen)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 minute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You project a phantasmal image of a creature’s worst fears. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or drop whatever it is holding and become frightened for the duration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While frightened by this spell, a creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a location where it doesn’t have line of sight to you, the creature can make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends for that creature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fear</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/fear</guid>
        
        <category>bard</category>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>warlock</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elemental Weapon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level transmutation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: Touch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentration, up to 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nonmagical weapon you touch becomes a magic weapon. Choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder. For the duration, the weapon has a +1 bonus to attack rolls and deals an extra 1d4 damage of the chosen type when it hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th or 6th level, the bonus to attack rolls increases to +2 and the extra damage increases to 2d4. When you use a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the bonus increases to +3 and the extra damage increases to 3d4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/elemental-weapon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/elemental-weapon</guid>
        
        <category>paladin</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dispel Magic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd-level abjuration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Range&lt;/strong&gt;: 120 feet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Components&lt;/strong&gt;: V, S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;: Instantaneous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose one creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of 4th level or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell’s level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/dispel-magic</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ephe.github.io/grimoire/spells/dispel-magic</guid>
        
        <category>bard</category>
        
        <category>cleric</category>
        
        <category>druid</category>
        
        <category>paladin</category>
        
        <category>sorcerer</category>
        
        <category>warlock</category>
        
        <category>wizard</category>
        
        <category>level3</category>
        
        
        <category>spells</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
